# 大爷教你们奇妙的招
Da Ye is teaching some useful tips today
# 这招绝对棒
It’s totally working.
# 好看吧 金黄
Look at the golden color
# 你听这声音震脑子都
Listen to the crispy crackling sound.
# 香酥鸭
Fragrant Crispy Duck
# 但是今天我也改良了一下
I’m making some improvement to this dish today.
# 叫香酥去骨鸭 脱骨了给
I am going to debone it.
# 香酥鸭本身来讲
Traditionally
# 按道理是带骨头的
We should not remove the bones
# 因为在酒店
But in our restaurant (popular among foreigners)
# 老外对带骨头的东西不太感兴趣
Non-Chinese guests do not like meat with bones.
# 这是鸭骚 得去掉
This part smells really bad, we have to remove it.
# 这是什么鸭 这是樱桃谷鸭小鸭子
(What breed is this duck?)
Small Peking Duck
# 老外吃带骨的头不灵
Foreigners don’t like meat with bones.
# 我们在操作当中就把骨头去掉
So let’s remove the bones already.
# 我再检查底下里头啊
Let me check the inside
# 肺啊肠子看还有没有
Maybe the lungs and intestines are still there
# 还真不错挺干净的
Nice, it’s properly cleaned
# 我抠过了
I checked it already
# 还有呢 这儿得剌一下
We also have to make a cut here
# 食管 我也给抽过了
I have also removed the windpipe
# 最后一个环节
The last step
# 没洗鸭鼻涕吧 没有
See, you forgot to clean the nose
(indeed)
# 你看 得给师父留一点 挤一下
See? You have to leave something for your master
(Just squeeze it)
# 收拾干净以后我们先撮盐
After cleaning, we need to rub some salt on it.
# 今天咱鸭子是蒸 蒸煮都行
Are we gonna steam it?
(Both steaming and boiling are fine)
# 蒸的立整 煮的水气大 对
Steaming will be neater than boiling. Boiling may make it watery.
(Right)
# 搓盐入味是吧 腌制
Rub the salt evenly to marinate it
# 尤其这个鸭腿多给揉搓揉搓
Especially around the legs, you need to rub it well.
# 过去咱们做香酥鸡香酥鸭
We use to make both chicken and duck like this
# 三叔 的那一句话怎么说的
Remember what I always say, San Shu?
# 一通百通
This is learning by analogy.
# 香酥鸡跟香酥鸭的意思是一样的
You can use the same recipe for chicken and duck
# 搓好以后装到盆里头就要进行腌制
After rubbing it with salt, let’s put it in the bowl to marinate.
# 桂皮 大料 花椒
Cinnamon, star anise, and Sichuan pepper
# 来点小茴香吗 不要
A bit fennel seeds, maybe?
(no)
# 黄酒腌上
Yellow Chinese cooking wine
# 如果着急有半小时就可以
Marinate at least 30 mins if you are in a rush.
# 但是我腌的要咸一点
You should use a bit more salt if you only marinate it for a short period of time.
# 腌一小时就腌的淡一点
Use less salt if you got a whole hour for marination.
# 隋坡你闻一下师父腌的这个味道
Sui Po, smell this.
# 从基础上味道就充足了
You have to marinate it through at the beginning.
# 跟网友要说清楚的
Let me explain to our followers
# 一会蒸的时候这些东西都不要取了
Make sure you leave everything here when you steam it.
# 就原封的蒸或者煮
Leave everything in when you steam or boil.
# 你看隋坡老师傅做老菜
When an old master cooks a traditional dish
# 其实没那么多原料
He keeps everything simple.
# 就那么简单
Simple as that
# 所有的食材是借味
spices bring out the flavor of the duck
# 不是说整个鸭子就转变成
But the seasoning should not take over.
# 桂皮味什么的 那就不对了
Like, the duck should not only taste like cinnamon
# 对原来本味没有了
Then the natural flavor of the duck (main course) is lost.
# 鸭子也好了今天不蒸了
OK the duck is ready. We will not steam it today, though
# 因为咱这蒸着别的呢
The steamer is being used for some other dish.
# 咱们改煮
So instead, we will boil it.
# 要蒸的话大火蒸一小时
If you were to steam it, you will need one hour on high heat.
# 这种（电）高压性质的
If you use an electronic pressure cooker
# 半小时就可以了
30 mins will do.
# 大爷现在往里放水了
Let’s pour the water in.
# 这水上没味我们还得补点盐
We need to add salt to it.
# 还得搁点酒
And some Chines cooking wine
# 您这到省事
That was easy.
# 一教网友网友回家都能做了
So that all of our followers can learn and make this at home.
# 你看没有四十分钟
See, in less that 40 minutes.
# 这是机器说的话
According to the machine.
# 鸭子已经熟了
The duck is ready.
# 你看怎么能看出鸭子烂没烂
How can you tell?
# 看俩腿它缩回去了
See how the legs shrank into the duck?
# 拿出来晾着
Take it out and let it rest.
# 这小鸭子咱们家里正好吃一个
This duck is just the right size for us today.
# 这肚子里边很重要
Pay attention to the inside of it.
# 把这汤给卸了
We need to pour it all out.
# 翻着 现在就可以炸
Flip it, and it’s almost ready for frying.
# 但是咱们说的是香酥去骨鸭
But we promised to take the bones off.
# 我们不香酥了我们俩就这么吃
(Forget about the frying, it’s good to eat for us already)
# 可以迫不及待了
(I can’t wait)
# 这鸭子给它晾一晾
Let it rest for a while.
# 待会我去骨
I will debone it later.
# 晾鸭子这个时间 干点啥
In the meantime
# 咱们炒点花椒
Let’s roast some Sichuan Peppercorns
# 这花椒一定是现磨
We must roast it freshly.
# 现焙的花椒香啊
(Freshly baked ones smells much better)
# 刚开始因为锅不太热开大火
We used high heat to bring the wok's temperature up.
# 咱们现在小火慢慢焙
Now let’s roast it on low heat.
# 就搁这上头 先这样晾着
Put it right here and let it rest a bit
# 晾一晾
For a little while.
# 一会拿擀面杖一擀
We will grind it with a rolling pin
# 你看原来是发红
Its color turned from red
# 现在有点发褐色了
To a bit of brown.
# 要这葱心 咱们切末
Now let’s chop the spring onion up.
# 这先搁一边
Put it aside
# 行啊有点劲
(Not bad, you still got the muscles)
# 不是有劲儿
Well not really
# 花椒潮气出去了
It’s easier to grind when it’s dried like this.
# 细听这个声音咔咔
Listen to the crackling sound.
# 看着啊
Watch this.
# 把大爷的葱又跟
So, Da Ye is mixing the spring onion
# 花椒大颗粒混合了
With the large pieces of the Sichuan Pepper
# 盐 这叫椒盐
Add some salt.
(This is called "the Sichuan Peppercorn Salt")
# 这叫葱椒盐
This is called "the Sichuan Peppercorn Salt, with scallions"
# 这个很少用
This is not used very often nowadays
# 这是个老的调味方法
It’s an old time seasoning mix.
# 为什么要用葱心
Why do you only use the inner part of the spring onion?
# 它润的湿的
We need its moisture.
# 用那个（葱叶）还容易糊
And the green leaves burn too quickly.
# 炸完了以后容易糊
Especially if you deep fry it.
# 这俩花椒盐出来了
OK now we have both types of “Peppercorn Salt” ready.
# 一个葱椒盐 一个花椒盐
One with spring onion and the other one without.
# 下边咱们调一个糊
Next, we need to make a batter.
# 网友们 大爷做菜简单漂亮
(See? Da Ye was always making it simple but beautiful)
# 在家容易上手
(Easy to follow at home)
# 面粉 还有搁点淀粉
(Egg), Flour, and some starch
# 说着说着这边就和上水了
(Mix it with water)
# 这个糊调好了
(OK the batter is ready)
# 不光是鸡蛋 还要加点水
We added both egg and water.
# 两份面粉 一份淀粉
Two portions of flour and one portion of starch.
# 二比一 它起什么作用呢
Why is it 2:1 ?
# 外边有点酥 挺实酥脆立得住
To make sure that it crisp up while maintaining its shape after frying.
# 这个工作准备好了
OK the preparation is done.
# 下一步开始拆鸭子
Now, let’s remove the bones.
# 这些东西都要弄走
We need to clean it up.
# 不弄走容易上当
Otherwise it might get you later.
# 下锅一炸的时候它崩
it may pop in the oil
# 把水给它它沾干
Wipe the excess moisture out.
# 鸭子很酥烂
The duck has been fully cooked
# 把这水管子开开  还烫
Get the water running, it’s still hot.
# 去骨是从脊背
We start from the back
# 先把鸭脖子去掉
First remove the neck
# 一扽往下一撸 走人
And then just take it up like that, voilà!
# 全下来了
Here it gose.
# 脊背的肉 大骨已经去掉了
The bones in the back is removed.
# 我开始剔鸭胸的骨头
I’ll now take care of the ribs.
# 这个最好是晾凉了以后再拆有型
It’s better to debone it when it’s completely cooled off, so that it can stay better in shape.
# 其实这小脆骨也挺好吃的
(These cartilages also taste very nice)
# 按着走
Keep pressing the meat
# 一会我吃这个
I’ll eat that later.
# 为什么要脱一个糊
Why do we need the batter?
# 你看这拆完以后
Well, after we have removed the bones,
# 鸭肉有的个别的可能会烂
Some parts of the meat may fall off
# 因为它很酥
Because we have cooked it through.
# 这个酥叫酥烂的这种酥法
You know, almost falling off the bones.
# 这块叫胸叉骨
This is the wishbone.
# 你看烂乎乎的别着急
(Don’t worry if it looks as if it’s all falling apart.)
# 呈现出来的最后还美
(It will look alright at the end)
# 吸水的目的就是待会
We need to remove the excessive moisture
# 挂糊的时候挂得住
So that the batter can stick with the meat.
# 不吸就变成稀糊了
Otherwise it may get too soggy.
# 你看这个当补丁给补上
Let me fill this up.
# 哪厚的哪薄的一点问题没有了
Alright it is now all even.
# 刚才我尝尝这鸭肉稍微淡点
I tasted it just now, it needs a bit more salt
# 来了葱椒盐
Here, the pepper salt with spring onion.
# 你看见没有
(See that)
# 大爷的事在这儿
(That’s the trick)
# 比如说外边吃个烤羊腿
Sometimes when you roast the leg of a lamb.
# 外边焦嫩但里边没味
Roasted nicely crispy outside, but it may lack some flavor inside.
# 剩了不少怎么办
What are you going to do with the leftover meat?
# 把葱椒盐往羊肉里边一抹
Put this on
# 外边挂一个糊 一炸
Make a batter, and fry.
# 大爷教你们奇妙的招
(Secret tip from Da Ye)
# 这招是绝对棒
(This is absolutely amazing)
# 三叔点火
San Shu, fire it up.
# 倒油
Oil
# 三叔咱也不过日子了
(That’s a lot of oil but I don’t care )
# 拍拍干粉易于挂糊
Coat it with some dry flour so that the batter can stick to it.
# 上糊下粉 大爷厉害
(Batter on the top and flour at the bottom. Nice!)
# 正合适 我这个干活比较靠谱
I am quite serious about it.
# 咱们油温大概在四成啊五成啊
What is the oil temperature? 130-150 ℃?
# 得七成 上来就定型
We need it around 200 ℃, so that the meat will keep the original shape
# 因为咱这鸭子是热的
Also, because our duck is still warm.
# 所以油温就高一点
So, it’s alright to use a higher temperature.
# 凉鸭子搁了一宿了那就得五成六成
But if you fry it after cooling it overnight, then you should use a lower temperature of around 150℃
# 刨出来了啊
(Now you know the secret!)
# 先定型 定完型以后再升温
First fix the shape, then we can let the temperature go up a bit.
# 再一炸 倍儿酥
Fry again, to make it extra crispy.
# 非常好下锅了
Good, let’s fry it
# 因为家里边一个是锅小
Sometimes you only have a small pan at home.
# 油可能不会用这么多
And perhaps you don’t want to use that much oil in the pan.
# 我们可以把这鸭子分成两半
You can also cut it in half.
# 家有家的做法饭店有饭店的做法
You don’t have to do it in the professional way, like what we do in the restaurant.
# 油升一下温 二次复炸
Heat it up and fry for the second time.
# 这是什么啊 起酥
(What’s that for? To crisp it up.)
# 冒烟了准备复炸
(It’s smoking now, time to fry.)
# 这属于大鼻涕泡
(The large bubbles means)
# 温度就正好
That it is at the right temperature.
# 你看这怎么样 非常好
What do you think?
(Very good)
# 好看吧 金黄
Isn’t that beautiful.
(Beautiful golden color)
# 马上就出锅了
Almost ready
# 其实这么炸也快
(It is quite fast to fry it this way.)
# 刚做完了以后吃
(You can enjoy it right afterwards)
# 吃出鸭子的鲜味来
(You can taste the freshness of the duck)
# 炸出金黄色
Get the golden color on.
# 开始装盘了
Let’s start plating.
# 给它翻过来装 看着就酥
Flip it over
(You can see how crispy it is)
# 闻着香啊 修边啊
Smells amazing
(Let’s trim it)
# 待会我吃边
(I will eat these edges.)
# 我这从来不剩头 您是垫底儿呢给
I never waste anything
(Are you going to put it underneath?)
# 你看见没有大爷做菜就是样
(See? That’s how a real master like Da Ye cooks)
# 把边上先切了 小象眼刀
(He is chopping the side parts first)
# 你听这酥不酥 震脑子都
Can you hear the crackling sound?
# 香味出来了啊
(Smells amazing.)
# 尤其是这葱椒盐的味儿
Especially the smell from the pepper salt and spring onion.
# 货卖一张皮是吧
It’s all about the presentations！
# 鸭胸是最好的一块肉
The breast is the best part of the duck.
# 听这的声音
(listen to that)
# 沙沙的
(The crackling sound)
# 您给我蘸一个椒盐的吧
Can you dip that piece in the Sichuan peppercorn salt for me?
# 甘香酥脆
Sweet, fragrant, tender, and crispy.
# 真是甘香酥脆 肉软嫩
(It truly is.)
# 还脆呢
It is still crispy.
# 鸭子脏腥味没有 绝了
(All the bad smell from the duck is gone, amazing)
# 谢谢 谢谢
(thanks thanks)
# 得嘞
(Alright!)
# 极好吃啊极好吃
Absolutely delicious.
# import ending.srt 00:09:59,200